 /*********************************************************************************************************\
 |*		 			Marwen Kraiem 260955202						  *|													
 \*********************************************************************************************************/

The scene (farm.xml): a farm containing three animals (pig, bunny and a cow) with trees a lake (reflective and refractive water), some eggs and 3 sources of lighting. 	

Extra features:

Reflection:
I added an attribute to material class "mirror" used to the material reflects rays or not.
Then, I generated the reflected ray. This ray is used to generate new intersections and between the reflected ray and objects. 
At this stage the color computation was repeated twice. 
so, I created a new function "generateColor (result, ray, space_rafraction_index,depth)" that compute color from the ray, the intersection results and the list of lights. 
The computation is done in a recusive way. File to test: Reflection&Refraction.xml


Refraction:
I added two others attributes to the material properties "n" (refractive index) and "refractive" (to see how each color is refracted).
Then, I computed the refracted ray and generate colors. File to test: Reflection&Refraction.xml (three refractive shperes in a reflective plane)


Quadrics:
To solve a quadratic equation of the intersection of the ray with the quadric:
First, equation to solve for t: t ^ 2 * (d. (A * d)) + t (2 * (d. (A * p)) - 2 * Bd) + p. (A * p) -2 * Bp = 0 (u.v is the dot product)
Then, given the solution t, we compute the intersection and the normal. File to test: Quadric.xml ( a refractive quadric in a reflective plane)


Depth of field blur:
To add depth of field blur to the code, I added three variables to the camera class "focus" (focal length), "eyeSamples" (number of shifted eye samples per pixel) and "blur" (define how blurry the objects out of focus). 
we modified the praser to let the user define these variables in the xml file. 
If we have (focus> 0), we modify the ray direction and the ray origin in the generateRay function. File to test: TwoSphersPlaneDOF.xml ( two shperes where the camera has a focus = 10, blur = 0.1, samples = 10)



Area light:
I added 3 variables to the Light class: "samples" (the number of samples of shadow rays), "u" and "v" (two edge vectors). if the type of the light is area then the form will be considered its corner. 
For each source of light of type area, we generate different source of light where the origin is r = c + ξ1 * u + ξ2 * v.
where ξ1 and ξ2 are uniform random numbers in the range [0, 1). File to test: Cornell.xml (cornell room with lighting area defined by corner (from) and two vectors (u and v))
